Paul McNamara

0400 991 376

paul.a.mcnamara@outlook.com

linkedin.com/in/paulmcnamarasoftware

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A highly motivated emerging software engineer with three years professional experience. I bring a new perspective, excellent work ethic and the ability to work exceptionally well under pressure. Currently seeking an internship to further my engineering experience and skills.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Software Engineering (Honours)
Diploma in Professional Engineering Practice
University of Technology Sydney

Mar 2019 – Dec 2023 (Projected)

- GPA 6.02 and WAM 79.79 (Distinction average).
- High Distinction in Engineering Communication.
- High Distinction in Data Structures and Algorithms.
- High Distinction in Applications Programming.

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer

Aug 2022 – Jan 2023

Gecko

- Developed web-based features satisfying customer requirements and solving their problems, resulting in a 22% increase in customer satisfaction ratings.
- Coordinated the development of several web-based features by overseeing and managing deliverables, resulting in the features being delivered on time.
- Identified weaknesses in the front-end development pipeline and implemented new technologies to increase productivity, resulting in more features shipped at higher quality.

Software Engineer

Feb 2021 – Aug 2021

Income Energy

- Developed a billing management system by collaborating with stakeholders, resulting in increased efficiencies for business operations and a better customer experience.
- Facilitated conference calls and meetings, fostering collaboration and ensuring discussions remained on topic, resulting in more productive calls.
- Worked independently on creating tools to speed up the development process resulting in quicker completion of action items.

Motion Designer

Dec 2016 – Dec 2018

PharmaCare

- Integrated interdisciplinary work from colleagues to design intricate commercials suitable for multiple formats, satisfying elicited requirements from clients.
- Delivered solutions to clients' problems relating to project scope, timeframe and deadlines, resulting in quality customer satisfaction.
- Developed plugins and scripts for 3D applications, allowing for a more efficient pipeline.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

- Languages: TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS, PHP, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Frameworks and libraries: Next.js, React, Vue, Svelte, GraphQL, ExpressJS, Flask.

Software

- MS Office: Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook.
- Management: Trello, ClickUp, GitHub.
- Adobe Suite: Photoshop, After Effects, InDesign, Premiere, Substance.
- Autodesk: Maya.

TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

Communication	Great written and oral communication skills demonstrated through my time working at Gecko by delivering web-based features that solved customer requirements
Teamwork	Exhibited strong collaboration at Gecko by utilising the agile development process to effectively cooperate within a team of five, increasing the efficiency and quality of deliverables.
Resilience	Consistently achieved and exceeded expectations in a fast-paced and high stress environment at Pharmacare and Gecko.
Organisation	Managed tasks and time effectively by prioritising tasks using agile methodologies, Fibonacci sequence and Trello.
Problem Solving	Solved customers' problems by eliciting their requirements and effectively developing web-based features.
Attention to Detail	Analysed customer requirements and user stories, and reviewed code effectively to ensure an optimised development pipeline.

REFEREES

Available upon request